Lara Shalab-Alsham

Software Engineer

Creative, detail-oriented software engineer with a deep interest in automation. Experienced in efficient product delivery and working with customers and teams across the country. Excited to cultivate a culture of innovation and collaboration on a team of brilliant engineers.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at ion8

July 2024 — Present

- Transformed Call Connector's architecture from a single-purpose tool into a robust, extensible integration platform by refactoring legacy code, enabling rapid addition of 5+ new app integrations and streamlining future development.
- Led demos for customers and provided direct technical support for the business development and sales teams.
- Architected Nucleus, a private PyPI solution that consolidated commonly used code, transforming a fragmented codebase into a maintainable, DRY ecosystem and accelerating new app integrations by 50%+.

Web Designer & Developer at Grand Living

Jan 2024 — Sept 2024

- Automated complex workflows, including developing a CRM integration that reduced months of manual labor to minutes.
- Developed a swift landing page system, reducing creation time by more than 75%, while upholding brand consistency.
- Achieved 100% reduction in JavaScript and PHP errors.

Manager of Logistics at Brightside Express LLC

May 2021 — Jan 2023

- Maintained expense sheets and managed a log of trips spanning 100,000+ miles.
- Coordinated freight with brokers across 45 states during the pandemic in order to ensure shelves remained stocked with essential items.
- Decreased annual fuel expenses by almost \$5000 through budgeting, leveraging fuel cost-saving programs and negotiating fuel surcharge with shippers.

Armed Forces Jul 2014 — Jul 2018

- Led teams of 10-50 soldiers through field missions.
- Organized staff and equipment into different training platoons involving thousands of recruits in the country's largest infantry training center.
- Maintained high levels of morale within the unit by leading team activities and cultivating a supportive team environment where all voices were heard.

VOLUNTEERING

Developer, Art/Dev Lead at Grundo's Cafe

Mar 2023 — Present

- Leading the art-development pipeline for Grundo's Cafe. Facilitating cross-team collaboration, authoring design specs, and managing the release of new content.
- Sole developer and maintainer of an extensive suite of administrative tools for developer and artist staff.
- Enhanced the manual process of uploading assets for new features by automating tasks, reducing the time needed to release features by over 80%.

Director of Web Development at FemArt Gallery

Apr 2024 — Oct 2024

- Developed a new, accessible and SEO-optimized website for the organization.
- Participated in monthly board meetings and assisted with technical needs.

CONTACT

437.313.7465

LSALSHAM@hotmail.com

devlarabar.com

aithub.com/devlarabar

linkedin.com/in/lara-sa

SKILLS

Python

Node.js

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

Next.js

Django

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Supabase

HTML

CSS

PHP

WordPress

Web Accessibility

Photoshop

Illustrator

InDesign

Figma

EDUCATION

Royal Military College

Bachelor's Degree